<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blockchain Partners]]></title><description><![CDATA[Blockchain Partners]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-1/research</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 12:25:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-1/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Innovation sets institutional funds in motion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advantages of the blockchain 1. Reducing costs One of the main benefits provided by the blockchain technology is that it helps to bring...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-1/post/time-is-money-1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd83745a6fc8f0294f421d1</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 20:33:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_5ac1a8054303475182cb80c93980952a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_808,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ashton Hettiarachi</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advantages of the blockchain</strong></p>

<p>1. Reducing costs</p>

<p>One of the main benefits provided by the blockchain technology is that it helps to bring down the cost of fundraising. This is especially relevant for small companies. The blockchain has made it possible for any project to issue its own tokens and for any investor in any part of the world to participate in the product’s development.</p>

<p>2. Eliminating lawyers and the paperwork</p>

<p>In the past, in order to conduct an IPO (Initial Public Offering), a company had to pass through many levels of hell acquiring licenses, hiring multiple lawyers and being bored under the heaps of paperwork. Issuing tokens on the blockchain helps to get rid of all these obstacles all at once.</p>

<p>3. Lower barriers for listing</p>

<p>Stock exchanges charged enormous sums of money for listing creating huge barriers for small and medium-sized companies. Cryptocurrency exchange platforms charge their fees for listing as well, but of these fees are way smaller than those on the traditional stock market. Also, it is much easier and cheaper to change the ownership of a crypto asset.</p>

<p><strong>Disadvantages of the blockchain</strong></p>

<p>However, despite all of these advantages, there are still some problems that prevent institutional investors from joining the blockchain technologies.</p>

<p>1. Legalization.</p>

<p>Not all there blockchain projects follow the rules such as anti money-laundering, know-your-customer, etc.</p>

<p>2. No need for transparency.</p>
<p>
Some institutional investors value privacy above the transparency provided by the blockchain. They don't want any third parties to see all the details of their transactions.</p>

<p>3. Immutability.</p>

<p>Once a transaction is verified on the blockchain it cannot be undone. This is one of the greatest strengths and, at the same time, one of the greatest weaknesses of cryptocurrencies. If you send your funds to a wrong address, or your wallet gets hacked, or you lose your privacy keys you will never be able to retrieve your money. Unless there will be invented the way to undo a transaction on the blockchain, security tokens will hardly see institutional money.</p>

<p>In order to overcome these obstacles, there are several projects that are currently creating private blockchains. Thus, the Swiss stock market’s Swiss Digital Exchange (SDX) is now developing a pilot project aiming to tokenize the following groups of assets:</p>

<p>●  Native tokens for SMEs</p>
<p>●  Tokenization of existing securities n the SIX Swiss Exchange</p>
<p>●  Tokenization of non-bankable assets</p>
<p>●  Tokenization of cryptocurrencies, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_5ac1a8054303475182cb80c93980952a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_808,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crypto Outlook 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bitcoin History Increases Mean-reversion Risk According to Bloomberg research, Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies in general are expected to...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-1/post/balancing-checkbooks</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd83745a6fc8f0294f421d0</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 20:33:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_f763949774584dc2b39ff6760db24452~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_816,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ashton Hettiarachi</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bitcoin History Increases Mean-reversion Risk</strong></p>

<p>According to Bloomberg research, Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies in general are expected to get more mature. The BTC price has been continuously staying above the support level of 1,500 USD. More bullish factors should come in order for the price to break through the 6,500 USD resistance level at which it Bitcoin has been traded mostly through 2018. The launch of ETF in the US would increase the strength of support, but Bitcoin is still not likely to break through the 6,500 USD level.</p>

<p>If the supply of tradable cryptos reaches another peak it would be an indicator of the bottoming prices. This process is seemingly starting right now. Cryptocurrency futures launched in December 2017 and the Bloomberg Galaxy Crypto Index in May 2018 brought forward increased regulation and further market adoption. With Bitcoin reaching 3,400 USD, the average yearly price would be around 1,800 USD.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_f763949774584dc2b39ff6760db24452~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_816,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Technical Analysis Points to Lower Levels of Support</strong></p>
<p>Indicators point to Bitcoin reaching the bottom</p>

<p>Record-High Shorts and Low Volatility. In 2019, Bitcoin is expected to form a base for recovery, but it will be at lower levels. Short-term indicators point to possible sharp rallies, however, the overall volatility most likely will be pretty low.</p>

<p>2018 ending below 2017's average price of $3,950 points to further weakness. In order for Bitcoins Foundation to solidify, this indicator should come along with new heights and lows in volatility and price momentum.</p>

<p>The graph has reached two thirds, record shorts and there’s a steep discount below the 50-week average, which points to the possible sharp rallies in the future. 180-day volatility still has a long way to go for the basing process to become more sustained. The history lessons show that low volatility is the number one indicator of bottom.</p>

<p>According to our estimation, which covers data from Tradingview.com and CBOE and CME futures, Bitcoin shorts have reached a new record. At the same time, there is a biggest annual mean price discount since January 2015 when there was the previous bottom. All this points to the fact that the market is oversold. On December 14th, the discount was equal to 41% matching the same index of 2011 and 2015.</p>

<p><strong>Bitcoin volatility is to reach new lows in 2019</strong></p>

<p>The 180-day measure made in the middle of December resulted in 64% which is still very far from the historical low of 41% from October 2015. At that time, Bitcoin surged by 36% showing the best results of the year and the level of volatility marked the beginning of the next bull run that peaked in 2017. The speed of that run will hardly be repeated as Bitcoin gets more mature and mainstream with many new trading tools appearing in the market.</p>
<p>The highest peak of volatility during the 3-year timeframe was in Q1 with the substantial level of speculation in the background. When volatility decreases, it’s a sign that the market gets more mature moving from a speculative digital asset to a real store of value.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_509a877cacfa4269bd11e130f7eb8c6d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_886,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>NVT set to dip into the bottom in 2019</strong></p>

<p>The NVT ratio points to Bitcoin moving away from the bear market. If you divide the pace of the plunge in the 30-day average of Bitcoin's market capitalization by the estimated transaction value from Blockchain.com, you will see that such and index was last observed by the end of 2014-15 price decline.</p>

<p>The lowest levels were reached in January, but there was no market reversal up until October. Now as the market is much more mature, the speed of price recovery will hardly be repeated at the same level.</p>

<p>The process of base-building will take much longer. An NTV close to 130 is far below its peak of 200+ in October, but it’s still above typical post-bear-market lows that are usually equal to 40.</p>

<p><strong>Bitcoin-Address Demand Proxy Stabilizing Lower</strong></p>

<p>As the market is unable to stay above 2017 lows in unique Bitcoin addresses, it serves as an indicator of prices getting even lower in 2019. According to Blockchain.com, the 30-day average of these addresses has finally recovered from the most acute decline in 2009. However, it still can’t break through resistance.</p>
<p>The demand for new addresses has been growing all through 2018, though. It shows that the prices were just too elevated. The Bitcoin price and the MVIS CryptoCompare Digital Assets 100 index are most likely getting more stable at a closer parity to addresses, a demand proxy for the broad market.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_1b955bdaae524a8e89457c15e2d5908f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_916,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Crypto Reshuffling and Culling Likely With Lower Prices in 2019</strong></p>

<p>All through 2018 there has been a trend towards decrease in prices and volatility and the issuing of new stable coins. In our opinion, 2019 will be practically the same. Tether, one of the eldest stablecoins in the market, with its increasing market capitalization is a good indicator of stability that the market needs so much.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_408c55a025794731b1e54f3506247d8c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_916,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In our opinion, the average price of Bitcoin is yet to see its lowest in 2019 with the total supply of cryptocurrencies reduced so much. 2015 was the only year when the price was lower while the number all cryptocurrencies increased according to the data available at coinmarketcap.com. As the market gets more mature, weaker cryptocurrencies will most likely be removed as well as the disparity between technology adoption and the hype around it.</p>

<p>If you check the top of coinmarketcap 5 years ago you will see that there are only 3 cryptocurrencies is that still hold their positions: Bitcoin, XRP and Litecoin. Half of those that were in the top 10 for the last 6 months are still there. By the end of 2019, only a small part of projects that are currently listed will still be afloat.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market Growth, Analysis]]></title><description><![CDATA[Crypto Market Users and Volume The graph below shows the total number of blockchain wallet users worldwide, from Q1 2015 to Q4 2018. The...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-1/post/modern-day-meetings</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd83745a6fc8f0294f421cd</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 20:33:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_6a0a68f3b5c643fc864c532e93da9f07~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_786,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ashton Hettiarachi</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Crypto Market Users and Volume</strong></p>

<p>The graph below shows the total number of blockchain wallet users worldwide, from Q1 2015 to Q4 2018. The number of registered cryptocurrency wallets has been growing ever since Bitcoin was created in 2009. By the end of 2018, it has reached almost 32 million.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_6a0a68f3b5c643fc864c532e93da9f07~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_786,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>On the following graph, you can see Bitcoin’s market capitalization (Q1 2012 - Q4 2018). This index is obtained by multiplying the total number of bitcoins in the circulation by the BTC price. The overall capitalization has grown from 0.04 billion USD in Q1 2012 up to 237.62 billion USD in Q4 2017. It has decreased down to 66.18 billion USD by the end of Q4 2018.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_be05975fbc81408c83dbcd6d2e4b430e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_722,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Volume by Country</strong></p>

<p>The analysis of the 46 country datasets presented at Local Bitcoins shows that Bitcoin trading is pretty concentrated within 5 countries. USA, Russia, UK, Venezuela, and China account for 72% of all trades that take place on the platform. This points to uneven BTC adoption across different regions.</p>
<p>In this analysis, we only review the data extracted from Local Bitcoins with its overall trading volume of 6.3 billion USD. This amount is just a small fraction of the global trading volume, but it’s enough to make correct conclusions about Bitcoin adoption.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_f16b4036489c4d97bf9a68cf15a953a7~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_536,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Share by Continent</strong></p>

<p>The analysis of Bitcoin trading share by continent reveals that the most active region is Asia with more than 2 billion USD invested in Bitcoin in total. China and Chinese investors make up around 620 million USD of that sum.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_db02c117cf1a4c6ca4ca4c104e80bfe1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_810,h_416,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Volume in the US</strong></p>

<p>The United States head the list of all countries by the overall Bitcoin trading volumes. In January, the US alone has invested 1.44 billion USD into Bitcoin 2019 which makes up a 22% share of the total BTC trading volume.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_d09c9e3dfc744437ad6776347b1c2630~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_706,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Volume in Russia</strong></p>

<p>Although trading Bitcoin is not officially permitted in Russia, this country takes the 2nd line by the overall trading volume. The statistics shows that Russian cryptocurrency investors have invested over 1 billion USD into cryptocurrencies and make up 16% of the total Bitcoin trading volumes.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_8170e54ef26f4c4eb1be09be7247240e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Volume in the United Kingdom</strong></p>

<p>The United Kingdom goes the 3rd in line with over 738 million USD invested in BTC and makes up one of the biggest markets. Its overall share of BTC trading volumes makes up 11% of the total sum. Also, the UK is home to the biggest number of legally registered cryptocurrency exchange markets.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_d763b8141e3642c29a4a032131588081~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_912,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Bitcoin Trading Volume in China</strong></p>

<p>As it’s already been mentioned above, over 2 billion USD has been invested in Bitcoin in Asia alone with China contributing around 620 million USD. China makes up around 10% of the overall BTC trading volume worldwide.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/de3f5b_867122b972cf4569b8b19d7e6ad4800c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_850,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Trading vs HODLing</strong></p>
<p>Typically, there are two things that cryptocurrency investors do their assets. They either hold (HODL) them for a long period of time waiting for them to grow in price, or they trade cryptocurrency trying to make profits on the short run.</p>

<p>For the new buys in cryptocurrencies, the general advice is to HODL their assets. This is an intentional misspelling which implies and implies holding your coins through ups and downs of the crypto market. Below, we are going to review pros and cons for both of strategies.</p>

<p><strong>Advantages of HODLing</strong></p>

<p>The main advantage of this strategy is its simplicity. All you have to do is to buy cryptocurrency, withdraw it to your wallet and sit still until its price increases. You have to be patient, though. You may live through numerous sleepless nights before you see your crypto portfolio grow in price, but it will surely pay off and make you feel like a god. Also, if cryptocurrencies are a subject to taxation in your region, this strategy will help you reduce the amount of taxes that you have to pay as you don't cash out your cryptos.</p>

<p><strong>Disadvantages of HODLing</strong></p>

<p>The main disadvantage associated with this strategy is related to emotions. New investors are typically attracted by cryptocurrencies when the market is at its peak and the prices are at the highest level. The downtrend always follows alter the highest peak and investors have to wait for a terribly long period time until their assets’ prices grow back again. This may be very difficult from the psychological point of view, especially for the newbies.</p>

<p><strong>Advantages of Trading</strong></p>

<p>The cryptocurrency market is pretty volatile in comparison with Forex and other traditional stock markets. While a 2% gain is a whole event on Forex and a daily course of action on stock markets, in cryptos it may be a question of 5 minutes time frame.</p>

<p><strong>Disadvantages of Trading</strong></p>

<p>Unless you're a professional trader who knows how to read candlestick graphs and all the possible signals to look out for, or unless you're simply lucky, most likely you will simply lose money. The cryptocurrency market is made up of manipulations which are designed to mislead newbies.</p>

<p><strong>Summing Up</strong></p>

<p>If you are a total newbie in cryptocurrencies, you should be extremely cautious when entering this unpredictable market. Select your strategy and keep up with it no matter what's going on with the market at the moment by putting out all emotions.</p>
<p>Here's what you should keep in mind when selecting whether you want to hold or trade:</p>
<p>●  HODLing is relatively simple, but requires a solid state of mind. Define your strategy and don't give in to your emotions through all ups and downs of the market.</p>
<p>●  Trading is more complex and requires more luck than knowledge from the newbies. If you're lucky enough you have some chances to significantly increase your profits. Otherwise get ready to lose most of your investments.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>